Spring break is over and we've
started our second year of high school.
You're in Class 4, huh?
I guess we're gonna be apart again.
But you're in Class 3, so we'll
have PE and stuff together.
Hey, Hananoi!
We're in the same class again.
Let's have a great year!
I'm in Class 3 too.
We've been in the same class forever,
Hotaru. Makes me wanna barf!
Even Shibamu is in Class 4.
But you'll have Keigo-kun with you.
I'm sure you'll be fine.
You've got me, right?
You're in a totally different world
from us girls.
Wh-What is it?
Hotaru-chan, you always call that
guy by his first name, right?
"That guy"?
Oh, you mean Keigo-kun?
Isn't it about time you start
using my first name too?
U-Um, did you just say something?
No, it was nothing.
Okay, I'll see you on the way home.
First names, huh...?
April is the season of change.
Episode 10
Our First Second Year
Yo, Hananoi!
Find anyone to celebrate your birthday with?
Whoa!
Oh, come on, Kei-chan!
Asami-san.
Yes?!
When did you start calling
this guy by his first name?
When? I think it was right
after we first met.
So it was important to start early...
Shibamu, good morning!
Good morning!
Let's have a great second year together.
All right. Please take your seats, everyone.
A new classroom.
New classmates.
A new normal...
Who is that upperclassman?! He's so cool!
...is already unfolding.
I wonder what grade he's in.
The Next Day
Hibiki
Thanks!
Let's eat lunch together!
Hibiki
Sorry!
I want to get used to
my new class, so I'm
going to eat lunch
with the girls here
for a while
Beg Ya Pardon
What?!
Oh well. It figures.
Yeah. But what should I do?
I'm supposed to eat with Hananoi-kun today.
Don't sweat it.
Hotaru-chan!
Let's have lunch together.
Wow!
Hananoi-kun, perfect timing!
I see.
You don't need to worry about me.
But I don't want to leave you alone, Shibamu.
Wow!
What are they talking about?
He's so cool!
Well, worst case, I eat by myself.
That doesn't bother me at all.
Boyfriend
Friends
Who do I put first
in a situation like this?
It would be best if the three
of us could eat together!
But I doubt Hananoi-kun would go for that...
Shibamura-san,
why don't you just eat with us?
Huh? D-Do you mean it?
Um, but it won't be just for today.
That's okay.
I've decided I can live with it.
Oh...
Okay, then let's find some other time
for just the two of us later on!
Sure.
Oh! I forgot to get a drink!
Sorry, I'll be right back!
Listen, I'm really sorry to impose like this.
It's fine.
Um, Hananoi-san, what do you do for lunch
when you don't eat with Hotaru-chan?
I find somewhere to eat alone.
Ah. Eating alone is easiest, isn't it?
But I guess everyone else hates it.
You really didn't need
to make a fuss about me, Hotaru.
Yeah, I guess it is easier.
Though I like eating with Hotaru-chan more.
What about you, Shibamura-san?
Well, I guess the same goes for me.
Then you don't have to
feel so bad about this.
Hey, you two! Thanks for waiting!
Chow time!
Hamburg steak!
But I really should save
the main dish for last!
Yum!
Ah, this is so fun.
It really is, isn't it?
Th-They agree on something?
Okay, should we start heading back?
Sorry, but we need a minute.
Why don't you go on, Shibamura-san?
Sure. Take your time.
What's up?
I'm thinking...
I won't get a chance
to hold you like this for a while.
I'm recharging.
I-I see.
Oh, right! Um, was lunch today okay with you?
If you really didn't like it, please tell me.
You don't need to worry about that.
I'm sure that past me would've
hated a situation like today's.
But I can tell that you really
care about me. It shows.
So I'm just getting my fill of you
to last me for a while.
I guess we should go back.
Huh?
Sorry. I need another ten seconds after all.
S-So, what did you think of lunch?
I thought it was pretty fun.
That's the most I've ever talked
with Hananoi-san.
He said that he likes eating with you
more than eating alone.
That really stuck with me.
Seems like you two are
really hitting it off. I'm glad.
I'm sure that past me would've
hated a situation like today's.
I wonder if I can talk to him about it now.
It's something I've been thinking about
but haven't had courage to bring up.
Friends, huh? I don't think I need any.
It seems like Hananoi-kun cares
a lot about his alone time.
So this never felt like something
I should push him on.
But things might not always be that way.
It's like something, bit by bit,
is changing inside him.
I can't take it anymore!
I've tried my hardest for two weeks,
but enough is enough!
As long as we get along,
we'll be friends eventually!
I'm so glad we're all eating together again!
Things are more exciting with Hibiki around.
Yeah, but you know,
now that I'm in class with Hananoi-kun,
it's so obvious how he goes
out of his way to be alone.
When I saw how he keeps to himself,
I kind of threw my hands up.
Um, actually, I wanted to ask
you two for advice about that.
Oh, yeah?
Things are back to normal, huh?
You must be happy.
Yeah.
S-So after this, I mean from now on,
if it's okay with you, will you eat
lunch with us, Hananoi-kun?
Um, but that sounds...
Oh! We can still have days
when it's just the two of us.
I mean the rest of the week.
If you'd rather eat alone,
we can just keep things the way they were.
But these past two weeks, you've been
talking like normal with Shibamu,
so as long as it would be
okay with you...
If anything, I wonder, would it be okay with you?
You've finally got some girl time together.
I don't mind at all!
But I'm sorry. I don't exactly know
how things are going to go.
I think it would be fun to hang out together,
but there's a chance it may not go over well.
But still...
I want to try it, and then we can decide
what's the most fun for us, Hananoi-kun!
All right. I'll think about it.
Okay!
Trying something new can be
scary and confusing at times,
but if it can make
the people I care about happy,
I want to do my part.
Yeah. Change isn't always a bad thing.
Hananoi-kun is the one who taught me that.
It's so warm today!
Eating outside was the right move.
Strawberry Milk
But man, Hananoi, is that all you got?
All right, all right. Want some of mine?
No way.
Then how about mine? I made extra today.
Wow, that looks so good!
You guys too, if you want.
Huh. It's unusual for you to cook.
Well, to tell you the truth,
I was practicing cooking for Saki-kun,
but since it was just practice,
my mom did most of the work.
Hmm? Who the heck is Saki?
No way... What?!
Hey, what's Hananoi's first name again?
Would you shut up a minute?
Yeah, I knew that would
embarrass him! I'm so sorry!
It was the day Hotaru had to go
to the vet for surgery...
U-Um, is that you over there, Yao-kun?
Wh-What's wrong?! Are you okay?
Should I get someone?
Don't tell anyone!
O-Okay.
Sohei-kun! Where are you?
Non-chan!
Hotaru-chan.
Hotaru?
Have you seen Sohei-kun?
I-I don't think he's over here.
Okay. Sohei-kun!
Everyone's looking for you, Yao-kun.
It might be better to hide
somewhere farther away.
Well, I'd better go.
Wait, Hotaru!
That was how I became friends with Hotako.
She shared the name
of a precious family member.
She was kind.
And she was always true to herself.
Whenever I was with her, I felt so relaxed.
She's the kind of person
you just want to see happy.
Someday, somewhere...
I hope you find someone
who makes you happy.
Otowa South Elementary
Hananoi (sixth grade, class 5)
Now dating
Hotako (sixth grade, class 1)
Me
Classmates
Does she know Hananoi went to our school?
Hmm...
Yao!
Wanna come to karaoke with everybody?
Sorry, I have work today.
U-Um, ever since you found that book
for me, I couldn't get you off my mind.
No thanks.
I have no interest in you whatsoever.
Man, he sure doesn't pull any punches.
Oh...
Sorry. I didn't mean to spy on you.
Do you get asked out a lot by random girls?
Huh?
Is that any of your business?
Well, no. I was just thinking how
tough that must be for Hinase.
She used to be so easygoing
in elementary school.
I guess I just worry about her.
Oh, speaking of which, didn't you
guys know each other before too?
The other day, when I was
flipping through my yearbook,
I saw a guy with your name in class 5.
Then I remembered we had a
transfer student in sixth grade.
Why didn't you say anything?
Hinase doesn't realize it either, does she?
I don't see any point in telling her
if she doesn't remember.
I don't particularly care
for who I was back then.
Oh... okay.
But still, isn't that something you should...
If you want to tell her, go ahead.
Yeah, I really can't figure him out.
He seems to put up a wall
with everyone, but...
Oh? What's that?
It was a birthday gift from Hinase-san.
Maybe he isn't such a bad guy after all.
Should I just drop it and not do anything?
Hananoi?
Oh, yeah! The transfer kid who wore glasses?
You ever hear anything about him being
friends with that Hinase girl from my class?
You mean Hotako-chan?
The nerdy girl you went out with?
Huh?!
People were spreading rumors, man.
Someone said they saw you two alone.
We were only talking about my dog!
Yeah, well, you were at least friends, right?
Who knows?
She told me she didn't
think we were that close.
And now we talk all the time,
but whenever I get close, she backs off.
She acts kinda cold, you know?
Maybe she hates me. I don't get it.
Wow, I never hear you
complain like this, Sohei.
Oh.
Was I complaining?
What the hell am I doing?
Hotako. Hotako!
Yao-kun, why do you always call me Hotako?
Don't you wanna call your friends
by their name or nickname?
F-Friends?
I guess we are friends!
Thank you very much for calling.
Yes. A picture book with animals?
Hmm. Animals, animals...
Yao-kun? Are you okay? Is something wrong?
What?! What happened?
Sorry, I know I'm at work.
Wh-Why don't you go in the back for now?
No, I'm good! I'll be fine.
Ah! There you are, Yao!
I was in the neighborhood,
so I thought I'd stop by.
I'm sorry, but that's not Yao-kun!
Huh? That's totally Yao.
I'm very sorry! Would you mind
seeing him some other time?
What's this about?
Who are you to him anyway?
I-I'm his friend!
Well, I'm his friend too!
I'm working right now.
Sorry, okay?
Well? Are you better now?
Uh, yeah.
Hotako, I'm real sorry about before.
No, I shouldn't have done that.
That name...
Huh?
You've gone back to calling me Hotako.
Oh, sorry!
No, it's okay! I think I've started
to understand how you feel.
It's hard to change what
you've always called someone.
It feels really weird and makes
you so nervous every time.
When he said I could take my time,
it was such a relief.
So... do you mean I can
keep calling you Hotako?
I guess I mean to make the switch
when it feels right to you.
Okay. That's a relief.
You sure never change, Yao-kun.
Huh?
You've always been sentimental about dogs.
Well, you don't change either, Hotako!
You've always been a terrible liar.
Huh?
Oh... This feeling.
It's been so long.
It feels like I'm floating.
When we laugh together,
it's like a weight off my shoulders.
I used to really love those moments.
Um, listen. I don't mean
anything weird by this, but...
Hotako, do you like me? Or dislike me?
Uh...
I...
I respect you!
R-Respect?
Yeah! Since before. I always have!
Really? You respect me, huh?
That's sort of flattering.
Why do I feel like this?
Hey, you said you wanted to find a way
to thank me after you guys came over to my house.
Yeah, I did.
Listen, Hotako...
I want to talk to you a lot more.
So, I was thinking, why don't
we all go somewhere again?
Huh?
A get-together?
Yeah.
I'm not trying to get you
to like me or nanything.
but can't we just talk like normal people?
I mean, she's probably worried about us too.
Do you really wanna keep putting
your girlfriend through that?